KEVIN LONG

Austin, TX

Phone: 512-975-0082 | Email: kevinjlong75@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/klong75 | GitHub: https://www.github.com/KLong75 | Portfolio: https://www.klong75.github.io/KLong_Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer. Bachelor of arts in theater. Have worked as a theater artist specializing in puppetry for over 20 years. At first glance coding may seem quite different from theater, however both are highly collaborative creative processes that require creative problem solving to reach a common goal by a deadline. Both require a focused group of people working together to build something. The tools and materials are just different. A career in the arts has often necessitated a day job. Extensive work experience in a variety of roles and industries including retail, food service, agriculture, manufacturing, and education. Have experienced technology in the workplace as both an asset and an obstacle. All of this real world experience informs thinking as a developer resulting in applications that are effective, intuitive, and easy to use. Adapts to new information and evolving circumstances. Excellent communication skills. Welcomes feedback. Always looking to grow and improve. Thrives on creative problem solving and collaboration. Experienced at meeting deadlines under pressure.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6+, SQL

Applications: Google, GitHub, MongoDB, Mongoose, Sequelize, MySQL, Express, React, Node,

Handlebars, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Material UI

PROJECTS

MUSICOLOGY - A MERN stack networking application for musicians.

- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/KLong75/musician-networking-app
- Deployed Application: https://musicology-umekev.herokuapp.com/
- Role: Primary author and project manager
- Tools: MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, React, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Material UI, bcrypt, JSON web tokens

Movies R Us - Allows users to browse titles by genre across all major subscription streaming services and link directly to a selected title on any streaming service that carries the title.

- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/KLong75/Movies-R-Us-KJ
- Deployed Application: https://klong75.github.io/Movies-R-Us-KJ/
- Role: Javascript
- Tools: HTML, Javascript, CSS, Watch Mode API

EXPERIENCE

Theater Artist 1998 - Present Various Locations

Worked with several different theater companies in a variety of capacities including puppeteer, actor, director, technical director, lighting designer, set designer, and theater technician. Key Accomplishments:

- Performed in 18 states and 2 foreign countries (South Korea and The Dominican Republic)
- Technical Director and Staff Artist for MayDay Parade and Festival (2001 2012) an annual outdoor giant puppet spectacle produced by In The Heart of the Beast Puppet and Mask Theater involving hundreds of performers attended by tens of thousands in Minneapolis, MN.
- Director for Country Day Creative Arts Festival Opening Ceremony (2007- 2011) an outdoor giant puppet spectacle involving over 100 student performers ages 6-13 in Metairie, LA.
- Created Muppet Style puppets of local tv news personalities for ABC affiliated KVUE News in Austin, TX and used the puppets to film promo spots for KVUE News and the Muppet Show.

First and Second Grade Teacher Austin Discovery School

2020 - 2021

Austin, TX

Utilized clear communication and critical thinking skills to develop and implement lesson plans for all subjects across two grade levels.

Key Accomplishment:

• Successfully developed and implemented an innovative online learning system for virtual learning during COVID. This experience led directly to an interest in coding.

Preschool Teacher Children's Discovery Center

2019 - 2020

Austin, TX

Lesson planning, supervision, care, and safety of a classroom of 12 two year old children. Keys to success were flexibility, adaptability, patience, multi-tasking, quick thinking, and a thick skin.

Manufacturer 2018 - 2019
Calton Cases Austin, TX

Fabrication and installation by hand of interiors for custom guitar, bass, banjo, mandolin, and violin cases using foam, fabric, and a variety of glues.

Procurement Supervisor University of TX, Athletics Nutrition Center

2017 - 2018

Austin, TX

Inventory management, ordering of all food and supplies, receiving orders, supervising stocking of all items received, researching new items, communicating with vendors, customer service, etc. Key Accomplishment:

• Developed and implemented an electronic ordering and inventory system.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development - Graduated 2022 University of Texas

Austin, TX

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Full Stack Web Development

Bachelor of Arts in Theater - Graduated 1998

Kirksville, MO